<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>chatterlab</title><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/</link><description>Recent content on chatterlab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/casillas-devcommcomp-spring2020-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/casillas-devcommcomp-spring2020-syllabus/</guid><description>!!! NOTE: Given ongoing pandemic and protest activity the grading scheme is being adjusted. Please check your email for more details about extended deadlines and options for finishing up the quarter. The deadlines listed below for the research proposal and exam are officially out of date as of June 1, 2020. The development of communicative competence Spring 2020: CHDV 38950, LING 38951, PSYC 38960, EDSO 38950
Tuesdays and Thursdays 15.30-16.50 Chicago time</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-active_attendance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-active_attendance/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Active attendance The Spring 2020 quarter gives us 16 class sessions together (Tuesdays and Thursdays for eight weeks). Students receive 1 point for each time they actively attend a class.
What is active attendance? I will ask myself the following questions after each class session. If the answers are &amp;lsquo;yes&amp;rsquo; to all three, the student receives 1 point. Otherwise they receive 0 points.
was the student logged in and responsive to greetings at the start and end of class?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-annotation_peer_grading/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-annotation_peer_grading/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Peer grading of presentations on mini studies Students will watch and grade each of their classmates&amp;rsquo; videos, giving scalar ratings on each of the following statements:
why and how the annotations were added is clearly explained the findings are clearly presented reference to class material is made when appropriate The rating scale for these three questions will be:
Disagree — Partly agree — Agree
Students will also give two very short open responses for each video:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-annotation_presentation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-annotation_presentation/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Presentation of mini study of conversation clips This assignment gives you the opportunity to present the findings of your additional annotation analysis to your fellow classmates. Your presentation should be a short video submitted at the start of class.
Full credit (4 points) for the presentation will be given when all of the following criteria are met:
the video is between 2 and 3 minutes long (maximum!) the video is submitted no later than the start of class on the day it&amp;rsquo;s due why and how the annotations were added is clearly explained, with reference to class material as appropriate the findings are clearly presented, with reference to class material as appropriate at least one weakness and one strength or one follow-up of the mini study are pointed out Presenting all this information in three minutes or less will be challenging; procrastination is not advised!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-annotation_proposal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-annotation_proposal/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Proposal for mini study of conversation clips Before adding the annotation of their choice to the conversation clips, students should first give a brief description of what they want to add and why. This proposal for additional annotation should be 300–500 words.
Full credit for the proposal (3 points) will be given when:
the proposal is 300–500 words the new annotations proposed are clearly defined a specific research question is asked it is clear how the new annotations can help answer the specific research question at least one forseeable issue or question relating to the proposed analysis is raised This proposal will be used as the basis for a one-on-one chat with Marisa about your mini study later in the week, so please turn them in by the beginning of class on May 12th.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-annotation_reflections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-annotation_reflections/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Annotations and reflections You will be asked to submit new annotations on your converation clips four times during this course. Each time you submit annotations, you should also submit a short paragraph reflecting on your experience. Each of the four submissions are worth up to three points.
Annotations All annotation will take place in ELAN. For each of the four submissions, the actual annotations you create will make up 2.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-debate_participation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-debate_participation/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Debate/&amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo; presentation participation Group debate: Turn-taking behaviors are universal to communicative systems There is one in-class debate planned in this course, and you will receive up to 1 point for your contribution.
In this debate, we will split up into groups and have a debate with one group arguing for the prompt and one group arguing against it. Groups will have a chance to work together to build their arguments and their response to the other group&amp;rsquo;s arguments.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-final_exam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-final_exam/</guid><description>Final exam This exam makes up 15% of your overall grade.
Please note: Marisa is happy to answer clarification questions about the prompts and grading rubrics but cannot provide any feedback about the specific content of your responses.
Short essay (up to 7 points) Please respond to ONE of the two prompts below. Your response should be between 1500 and 2000 words (~3–4 pages) and include accurate, appropriate references to at least six of the papers we read in the course.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-reading_notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-reading_notes/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Reading notes This course has a total of 36 required readings, but notes are only required for 30 of them. Students are allowed to pick which 30 readings to submit notes for. Each reading notes submission is worth 1 point (max 30 points). Of course students are welcome to take notes on all 36 readings, if desired ;)
Just in case you missed it, reading notes are 30% of your grade in this course!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-research_proposal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-research_proposal/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Research proposal The research proposal makes up 12% of your overall grade. Students are encouraged to focus on research topics that either link to their other areas of expertise or their favorite topics introduced during the course. Marisa will grade each one with the following questions in mind:
Is the research question clear, specific, and answerable? Is the research question novel and/or creative in some way? Does the proposed method of study and the proposed analysis give a targeted answer to the research question?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-research_proposal_subparts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/instructions-research_proposal_subparts/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Research proposal sub-part submissions A significant component of this course is the development of a proposal for research. In order to prevent last-minute preparation of this time-consuming task, drafts for three subsections of the proposal will be due in advance of the final deadline (1 point each), as follows:
Outline of the proposal For full credit (1 point), students should submit an outline containing the following sections with a list of notes and/or bulleted sub-topics beneath each one:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/notes/notes-outline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/notes/notes-outline/</guid><description>Bibliographic info Date Text body notes &amp;hellip; Critical and clarificatory questions and ideas Relation to my current projects Associated phenomena to consider covering in class Further reading Probably should have a look at For funsies Overall impressions</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/notes/week02lecture01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/spring2020/course_instructions/notes/week02lecture01/</guid><description>Levinson, S. C. (1995). Interactional biases in human thinking. In E. N. Goody (Ed.), Social intelligence and interaction (pp. 221-260). Cambridge, UK: Cambridge University Press. 30 March 2020 The thesis As nicely laid out up front:
Communication is impossible in the sense of logical signal encoding/decoding Despite this, humans communicate effectively all the time To do so they must use non-logical heuristics and some kinds of special reasoning For communication to work so well so often humans also need to keep these heuristics and modes of reasoning at the front of their minds at all times The consequence of which is that the same heuristics/reasoning affect cognition in non-communicative contexts (think, e.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/winter2021/casillas-bbc-winter2021-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/winter2021/casillas-bbc-winter2021-syllabus/</guid><description>Blooming, Buzzing Confusion Making Sense of Language in the First Few Years of Life Winter 2021: CHDV 23010
Tuesdays and Thursdays 12:30pm-1:50pm Chicago time
Office hours: Wednesdays 4:00pm–5:00pm Chicago time, or by appointment.
NOTE: This course is taking place remotely; email the instructor if you need access to the relevant meeting and coursework links.
Instructor: Marisa Casillas (mcasillas@uchicago.edu)
This course examines the social and cognitive mechanisms that drive language learning in the first few years of life.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/methods_presentations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/methods_presentations/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Methods presentations Each student is expected to participate in two methods presentations. Students earn up to 10 points (10% of the total grade) for each one.
This is a groupwork project, but group members will have an opportunity to report on individual contributions. There are three primary components to each presentation:
Give a 20-minute pre-recorded mini lecture that introduces a method and gives some sort of demonstration of how the method is implemented and how it appears to participants.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-1/</guid><description>Mini essay exam 1 Please use information from the readings, lectures, and in-class sessions to inform your answers. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to look up other sources, but you should always cite anything you use (even readings from our course). Be careful about re-using phrasings and concepts from out-of-class sources; there&amp;rsquo;s lots of information out there and not all of it is accurate. Your source citations do not count toward your maximum word count.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-2/</guid><description>Mini essay exam 2 Please use information from the readings, lectures, and in-class sessions to inform your answers. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to look up other sources, but you should always cite anything you use (even readings from our course). Be careful about re-using phrasings and concepts from out-of-class sources; there&amp;rsquo;s lots of information out there and not all of it is accurate. Your source citations do not count toward your maximum word count.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-3/</guid><description>Mini essay exam 3 Please use information from the readings, lectures, and in-class sessions to inform your answers. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to look up other sources, but you should always cite anything you use (even readings from our course). Be careful about re-using phrasings and concepts from out-of-class sources; there&amp;rsquo;s lots of information out there and not all of it is accurate. Your source citations do not count toward your maximum word count.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/mini_essay_exams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/mini_essay_exams/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Mini essay exams Three times throughout the quarter, undergraduate students will be expected to complete a mini essay exam. Each mini essay exam requires students to give ~500 word responses to two prompts. The exams are take-home and open-book; students have one week to complete each exam. Each exam is worth a total of 10 points (10% of the total grade) as follows:
Mini essay exam 1:
Response 1 (5 points max)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/participation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/participation/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Participation Participation points (up to 20 points/20% of the final grade) can be earned in two ways:
Active attendance during class sessions Visits to office hours The Winter 2021 quarter gives us 18 class sessions together (Tuesdays and Thursdays for nine weeks). Students receive 1 point for each time they actively attend a class (see below).
Students will receive 2 points for an office hours discussion with Marisa.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/reading_notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/reading_notes/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Reading notes This course includes up to 39 readings. Notes for required readings are due by the start of class. Please have your notes accessible during class.
Undergraduates
Undergraduate students will be assigned a total of 26 readings, but notes are only required for 24 of them. Each reading notes submission is worth 1.25 points each (maximum 30 points; 30% of the final grade). Students can choose for themselves which of the readings they would like to submit notes for.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/squibs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/squibs/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Squibs Over the quarter, graduate students are expected to produce six very brief (~1500–2500 word) papers on the topic of their choice related to course content. These &amp;ldquo;squibs&amp;rdquo; are used to engage further with ideas from the readings and, hopefully, to develop new ideas that can feed into the graduate student&amp;rsquo;s core work.**
What is a squib? Squibs are personal to your research interests—they are here for you to make concrete connections with what we are discussing in class and what you are thinking about in your Masters/PhD work.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/alexander-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/alexander-aboutme/</guid><description>[Alex]ander Stern (he/him/his) About me I am a fourth-year undergraduate student at the University of Chicago studying Linguistics and Urban Studies. I joined the chatterlab as a research assistant in June 2022. At the confluence of my academic interests, I want to investigate how language mediates an individual’s interactions with their society.
Contact Email: alexanderstern@uchicago.edu</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/alexk-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/alexk-aboutme/</guid><description>Alex Klerman (he/him/his) I am a second year undergraduate at the University of Chicago studying mathematics and psychology. I joined the Chatter Lab summer of 2023 and am most interested in learning how the mechanisms behind early language acquisition change across cultures.
Contact Email: alexklerman@uchicago.edu</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/carla-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/carla-aboutme/</guid><description>Carla Escalante (she/her/hers) About me I am a fourth year undergraduate studying linguistics and biochemistry at the University of Chicago. I joined the chatter lab as a research assistant in January of 2023. I am interested in language acquisition in early childhood, particularly in multilingual environments.
Contact Email: cdescalante@uchicago.edu</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/isabella-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/isabella-aboutme/</guid><description>Isabella Di Giovanni (she/her) About me I am a second year PhD student in the Department of Comparative Human Development at the University of Chicago. I received my BA from Cornell University, where I studied Linguistics and Psychology with a minor in Cognitive Science. As an undergrad I worked with Professor Michael Goldstein and was involved in multiple research projects exploring early language learning in social contexts. Broadly, I am interested in language acquisition and development in social contexts, and in cross-linguistic and cross-cultural comparison.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/jordyn-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/jordyn-aboutme/</guid><description>Jordyn Martin (she/her/hers) About me I joined the Chatter Lab in January of 2023. I am continuing my work in the lab as a post-bacc researcher after completing my BA in Psychology. I am interested in how children use language to form concepts of identity and social belonging.
Contact Email: jordynmartin@uchicago.edu</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/kennedy-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/kennedy-aboutme/</guid><description>Kennedy Casey (she/her/hers) About me I am the current lab manager. I joined the chatter lab in summer 2021 after completing my BA degree at Princeton University, where I concentrated in Psychology and also studied Cognitive Science, Linguistics, and Neuroscience. During undergrad, I worked primarily with Dr. Casey Lew-Williams, and my thesis research combined eye-tracking and corpus-based observational methods to investigate how infants learn and represent some of their earliest words.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/lizzie-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/lizzie-aboutme/</guid><description>Lizzie Mickiewicz (she/her/hers) About me I am a fourth year undergraduate student majoring in psychology and neuroscience at the University of Chicago. I am interested in exploring how cognitive processes influence language and vice versa. Specifically, I am fascinated by the idea of music as a language and means of communication, and I would like to study music medicine in the future.
Publications Casey, K., Elliott, M., Mickiewicz, E., Silva Mandujano, A.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/marisa-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/marisa-aboutme/</guid><description>Principal investigator Dr. Marisa Casillas Photo credit: Erielle Bakkum
About Broadly speaking, I am interested in exploring how cognitive and social processes shape the ways in which we learn, perceive, and produce language. My primary research examines the relationship between communicative skills and linguistic processing in children and adults. I use a combination of experimental- and observation-based methods to comparatively investigate these processes in both urban, Western contexts and rural, Indigenous contexts.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/ruby-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/ruby-aboutme/</guid><description>Ruby Swensen Hi! My name is Ruby Swensen. I am in my second year as an undergraduate student studying linguistics with an emphasis in American Sign Language and a special interest in comparative human development. I joined the Chatter Lab in January 2023 excited to learn more about the many applications of language on human interaction and behavior. When I’m not studying or working in the lab, I love to go ice skating on the midway!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/sarah-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/sarah-aboutme/</guid><description>Sarah Sommer (she/her/hers) About me I am a fourth year undergrad double majoring in Comparative Human Development and English at the University of Chicago. I joined the lab in June of 2022 and I am interested in language development across different social and cultural settings.
Contact Email: ssommer@uchicago.edu</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/sarahk-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/sarahk-aboutme/</guid><description>Sarah Kelso (she/her/hers) About me I am a fourth year studying Psychology and Comparative Human Development. I joined the Chatter Lab in April 2023. I am especially interested in childhood development and often find myself drawn to topics involving language acquisition, but I am also interested in mental health and psychiatric disorders.
Contact Email: sarahkelso@uchicago.edu</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/subin-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/subin-aboutme/</guid><description>Subin Kim (she/her/hers) About me I joined the Chatter Lab in summer 2023 after graduating from the University of Pennsylvania with majors in Linguistics and Computer Information Science. During undergrad, I worked primarily with Dr. Delphine Dahan to study how we interpret questions in conversation. My primary research interests are in the intersections of psycholinguistics, computational linguistics, and language acquisition, with a focus on natural conversation.
Contact Email: subinkim@uchicago.edu</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/yuchen-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/yuchen-aboutme/</guid><description>Yuchen Jin (she/her/hers) About me I am a doctoral student in the Department of Comparative Human Development. Before coming to Chicago, I completed my BA in Education at Zhejiang University and Ed.M. in Human Development and Psychology at Harvard University. Broadly, my research interests include child lingusitic and communicative development, parent-child interaction, and in particular, how children become adapted to conversational turn-taking.
Contact Email: yuchenjin@uchicago.edu</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/contact/</guid><description>chatter at us! You can reach the chatterlab by calling (773) 702-1216.
Please send questions, comments, and suggestions directly to Dr. Marisa Casillas or to chatterlab@uchicago.edu.
Looking for open positions? You can find more information here!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/casillas-bbc-winter2023-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/casillas-bbc-winter2023-syllabus/</guid><description>Blooming, Buzzing Confusion Making Sense of Language in the First Few Years of Life Winter 2023: CHDV 23010
Tuesdays and Thursdays 3:30pm-4:50pm
This course examines the social and cognitive mechanisms that drive language learning in the first few years of life. Nearly all children learn the language(s) of their community, despite the fact that human languages and caregiving practices offer immense diversity around the globe. What enables the learning system to adapt so robustly to the environment it finds itself in?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/methods_presentations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/methods_presentations/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Methods presentations Each student is expected to participate in one methods presentation. Students earn up to 10 points (10% of the total grade) for their presentation project.
This is a groupwork project, but group members will have an opportunity to report on individual contributions. There are three primary components to each presentation:
Give a 20-minute pre-recorded mini lecture that introduces a method and gives some sort of demonstration of how the method is implemented and how it appears to participants.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-1/</guid><description>Mini essay exam 1 Please use information from the readings, lectures, and in-class discussions to inform your answers. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to look up other sources, but you should always cite anything you use (even readings from our course).
Avoid long and/or frequent direct quotations and focus on sources. Your source citations do not count toward your maximum word count.
What is statistical learning? (300–500 words) Describe (a) what statistical learning is (at a broad level) and why researchers are interested in measuring it for language development, (b) describe at least three concrete examples of different types of statistical learning, and (c) relate the work on statistical learning that you mention to the idea of learning &amp;ldquo;mechanisms&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-2/</guid><description>Mini essay exam 2 Please use information from the readings, lectures, and in-class discussions to inform your answers. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to look up other sources, but you should always cite anything you use (even readings from our course).
Avoid long and/or frequent direct quotations and focus on sources. Your source citations do not count toward your maximum word count.
Writing a grant to study the noun bias (500–750 words) Imagine that you are writing to the university to secure funding so that you can conduct an study on word learning.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-3/</guid><description>Mini essay exam 3 Please use information from the readings, lectures, and in-class discussions to inform your answers. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to look up other sources, but you should always cite anything you use (even readings from our course).
Avoid long and/or frequent direct quotations and focus on sources. Your source citations do not count toward your maximum word count.
Blooming and buzzing, but confusing? (500–750 words) In this course we have covered four major factors that influence how children learn language (i.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini_essay_exams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini_essay_exams/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Mini essay exams Three times throughout the quarter, students will be expected to complete a mini essay exam. Each mini essay exam requires students to give ~500 word responses to two prompts. The exams are take-home and open-book; students have one week to complete each exam. Each exam is worth a total of 10 points (10% of the total grade) as follows:
Mini essay exam 1:
Response 1 (5 points max)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/participation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/participation/</guid><description>Participation as active attendance I will ask myself the following questions after each class session. If the answers are &amp;lsquo;yes&amp;rsquo; to at least two of the three, the student will receive full credit for participation that session. Otherwise the student will receive receive no credit for the session.
Did the student attend? Did the student ask one or more questions or comments? Did the student respond to questions from others or substantially contribute to group activities?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/d2m2022/casillas-d2m-winter2022-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/d2m2022/casillas-d2m-winter2022-syllabus/</guid><description>From Data to Manuscript in R Winter 2022: CHDV 20550/30550, MACS 30550, MAPS 30550, PSYC 30550
Tuesdays and Thursdays 09.30-10.50 Chicago time
Office hours: Tuesdays 11.00–12.30 in Rosenwald 318A or by appointment
Instructor: Marisa Casillas (mcasillas@uchicago.edu)
This course tackles the basic skills needed to build an integrated research report with the R programming language. We will cover every step from data to manuscript including: Using R&amp;rsquo;s libraries to clean up and re-format messy datasets, preparing data sets for analysis, running statistical tools, generating clear and attractive figures and tables, and knitting those bits of code together with your manuscript writing.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/d2m2022/course_instructions/instructions-data_selection_guidelines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/d2m2022/course_instructions/instructions-data_selection_guidelines/</guid><description>Data selection guidelines You must have a dataset to work with over the course of this quarter. It should ideally be a dataset that is urgently important to you and that you want to write up into a scientific report now/soon. Those in this &amp;ldquo;ideal&amp;rdquo; situation are certain to get the most out of this course.
What constitutes an appropriate, ready dataset is hard to comprehensively define. But here are a few core features that the dataset should have for the purposes of this course (and for quantitative/automated analysis and open, replicable science in general, though not strictly):</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2022/casillas-devcommcomp-winter2022-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2022/casillas-devcommcomp-winter2022-syllabus/</guid><description>The development of communicative competence Winter 2022: CHDV 38950, PSYC 38960, LING 38951, EDSO 38950
Tuesdays and Thursdays 14.00-15.20 Chicago time
Office hours: Tuesdays 15.30–16.30 in Rosenwald 318A or by appointment
Instructor: Marisa Casillas (mcasillas@uchicago.edu)
This course examines the emergence of communicative skills in humans. We will discuss the proposed cognitive, developmental, and evolutionary roots of communicative behaviors, with a focus on current gaps in our knowledge and possible pathways forward.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2022/course_instructions/instructions-debate_participation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2022/course_instructions/instructions-debate_participation/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Debate/&amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo; presentation participation Group debate: Turn-taking behaviors are universal to communicative systems There is one in-class debate planned in this course, and you will receive up to 1 point for your contribution.
In this debate, we will split up into groups and have a debate with one group arguing for the prompt and one group arguing against it. Groups will have a chance to work together to build their arguments and their response to the other group&amp;rsquo;s arguments.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2022/course_instructions/participation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2022/course_instructions/participation/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Active attendance The Winter 2022 quarter gives us 18 class sessions together (Tuesdays and Thursdays for nine weeks). Students receive 1 point for each time they actively attend a class. The last 2 points for participation come from contributions to the two class debate and turn-taking feature presentations.
Active attendance at class sessions I will ask myself the following questions after each class session. If the answers are &amp;lsquo;yes&amp;rsquo; to both, the student receives 1 point.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2022/course_instructions/reading_notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2022/course_instructions/reading_notes/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Reading notes This course has a total of 36 assigned readings, but notes are only required for 30 of them. Students are allowed to pick which 30 readings to submit notes for. Each reading notes submission is worth 1.5 points (max 45 points). Of course students are welcome to take notes on all 36 readings, if desired ;)
Just in case you missed it, reading notes are 45% of your grade in this course!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2022/course_instructions/research_proposal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2022/course_instructions/research_proposal/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Research proposal The research proposal makes up 20% of your overall grade, including up to 2% for your class presentation of the proposal and up to 18% for your full written proposal that is due during finals week. Students are encouraged to focus on research topics that either link to their other areas of expertise or their favorite topics introduced during the course.
Flash presentation of the proposed research Students will present the basic idea of their research proposal to their fellow classmates.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2022/course_instructions/transcription_mini_project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2022/course_instructions/transcription_mini_project/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Transcription mini project Transcription mini projects have three sub-parts, as follows: (1) Annotation and reflection submission, (2) proposal of mini research question, and (3) flash presentation of findings.
Annotation and reflection submission You will be asked to submit new annotations on your converation clips four times during this course. Each time you submit annotations, you should also submit a short paragraph reflecting on your experience. Each of the four submissions are worth up to three points.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2022/casillas-hli-spring2022-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2022/casillas-hli-spring2022-syllabus/</guid><description>Human language and interaction Spring 2022: CHDV 23100, LING 21150, PSYC 23120, EDSO 23101
Tuesdays and Thursdays 9:30am-10:50am Chicago time
Language may be learned by individuals, but we most often use it for communication between groups. How is it that we manage to transmit our internal thoughts to others&amp;rsquo; minds? How is it that we can understand what others mean to express to us? Whether we are greeting a passerby, ordering a meal, or debating politics, there are a number of invisible processes that bring language to life in the space between individuals.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2022/miniassignment1-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2022/miniassignment1-rubric/</guid><description>Mini assignment 1 rubric [main page]
Assignment evaluation questions In assessing submissions for mini assignment 1, the grader will ask themselves the following questions, answering each on the scale of:
0 = grossly incomplete/not addressed
1 = needs significant work
2 = minimally fulfills requirements
3 = good effort, but with room for improvement
4 = excellent and above expectations
A. Is the example thoughtfully selected?: The joint activity selected by the student should be a clear case of a joint activity that is highly distinct from the (many) examples presented in the readings, lectures, and questions that came up during lecture.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2022/miniassignment2-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2022/miniassignment2-rubric/</guid><description>Mini assignment 2 rubric [main page]
Assignment evaluation questions In assessing submissions for mini assignment 2, the grader will ask themselves the following questions, answering each on the scale of:
0 = grossly incomplete/not addressed
1 = needs significant work
2 = minimally fulfills requirements
3 = good effort, but with room for improvement
4 = excellent and above expectations
A. Is the game thoughtfully designed?: The schelling game should be clearly distinct from any of the examples in class.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2022/miniassignment3-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2022/miniassignment3-rubric/</guid><description>Mini assignment 3 rubric [main page]
Assignment evaluation questions In assessing submissions for mini assignment 3, the grader will ask themselves the following questions, answering each on the scale of:
0 = grossly incomplete/not addressed
1 = needs significant work
2 = minimally fulfills requirements
3 = good effort, but with room for improvement
4 = excellent and above expectations
A. Are the examples clear and creatively varied?: You should choose your examples from sources that we (the graders) have access to.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2022/miniassignment4-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2022/miniassignment4-rubric/</guid><description>Mini assignment 4 rubric [main page]
Assignment evaluation questions In assessing submissions for mini assignment 4, the grader will ask themselves the following questions, answering each on the scale of:
0 = grossly incomplete/not addressed
1 = needs significant work
2 = minimally fulfills requirements
3 = good effort, but with room for improvement
4 = excellent and above expectations
A. Do the selected gestures illustrate course concepts in a thoughtful or innovative way?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2022/scientificreport-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2022/scientificreport-rubric/</guid><description>Scientific report rubric [main page]
Please see the lecture slides on writing scientific reports before you read this rubric and make a plan for your paper.
Structure and format Your paper should have headings and subheadings with the following structure:
Title, student number, and word count Abstract Introduction Study 1 Method Results Study 2 * (Proposed) Method * (Anticipated) Results General discussion References It should be submitted as a Microsoft Word document (NOT a pdf) and should be 1.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/casillas-hli-spring2023-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/casillas-hli-spring2023-syllabus/</guid><description>Human language and interaction Spring 2023: CHDV 23100, LING 21150, PSYC 23120, EDSO 23101
Tuesdays and Thursdays 9:30am-10:50am Chicago time
Language may be learned by individuals, but we most often use it for communication between groups. How is it that we manage to transmit our internal thoughts to others&amp;rsquo; minds? How is it that we can understand what others mean to express to us? Whether we are greeting a passerby, ordering a meal, or debating politics, there are a number of invisible processes that bring language to life in the space between individuals.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment1-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment1-rubric/</guid><description>Mini assignment 1 rubric [main page]
Assignment evaluation questions In assessing submissions for mini assignment 1, the grader will ask themselves the following questions, answering each on the scale of:
0 = grossly incomplete/not addressed
1 = needs significant work
2 = minimally fulfills requirements
3 = good effort, but with room for improvement
4 = excellent and above expectations
A. Is the example thoughtfully selected?: The joint activity selected by the student should be a clear case of a joint activity that is highly distinct from the (many) examples presented in the readings, lectures, and questions that came up during lecture.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment2-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment2-rubric/</guid><description>Mini assignment 2 rubric [main page]
Assignment evaluation questions In assessing submissions for mini assignment 2, the grader will ask themselves the following questions, answering each on the scale of:
0 = grossly incomplete/not addressed
1 = needs significant work
2 = minimally fulfills requirements
3 = good effort, but with room for improvement
4 = excellent and above expectations
A. Is the game thoughtfully designed?: The schelling game should be clearly distinct from any of the examples in class.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment3-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment3-rubric/</guid><description>Mini assignment 3 rubric [main page]
Assignment evaluation questions In assessing submissions for mini assignment 3, the grader will ask themselves the following questions, answering each on the scale of:
0 = grossly incomplete/not addressed
1 = needs significant work
2 = minimally fulfills requirements
3 = good effort, but with room for improvement
4 = excellent and above expectations
A. Are the examples clear and creatively varied?: You should choose your examples from sources that we (the graders) have access to.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment4-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment4-rubric/</guid><description>Mini assignment 4 rubric [main page]
Assignment evaluation questions In assessing submissions for mini assignment 4, the grader will ask themselves the following questions, answering each on the scale of:
0 = grossly incomplete/not addressed
1 = needs significant work
2 = minimally fulfills requirements
3 = good effort, but with room for improvement
4 = excellent and above expectations
A. Do the selected gestures illustrate course concepts in a thoughtful or innovative way?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/scientificreport-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/scientificreport-rubric/</guid><description>Scientific report rubric [main page]
Please see the lecture slides on writing scientific reports before you read this rubric and make a plan for your paper.
Structure and format Your paper should have headings and subheadings with the following structure:
Title, student number, and word count Abstract Introduction Study 1 Method Results Study 2 Proposed Method Anticipated Results General discussion References It should be submitted as a Microsoft Word document (NOT a pdf) and should be 1.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/casillas-mcdr-winter2023-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/casillas-mcdr-winter2023-syllabus/</guid><description>Methods in Child Development Research Winter 2023: CHDV 23150, CHST 23150, EDSO 23150/33150, LING 33150, PSYC 23155/33150
Tuesdays and Thursdays 2:00pm-3:20pm Chicago time
This course engages with one current topic (the topic differs each year) from research on child social and/or language development. We will read and discuss a collection of research studies related to this topic to gain familiarity with its primary questions, theories, and methods. We will also, together as a class, conduct a replication of an experiment- or recording-based research study related to the topic.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/course-instructions/data_collection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/course-instructions/data_collection/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Data collection report Each student is expected to participate in at least one live data collection session, observing silently and under the supervision of a trained member of Dr. Casillas&amp;rsquo;s lab. Students are required to report on what they learned from the experience. The report can come in pretty much any form you can imagine submitting to Canvas: a brief (~0.5–1 page) written response to the questions below, a short story/poem/interpretive dance or song describing the experience, a collage or drawn/painted image, a sequence of relevant tiktoks, etc.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/course-instructions/final_exam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/course-instructions/final_exam/</guid><description>Final exam Please use information from the readings, lectures, and in-class discussions to inform your answers. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to look up other sources, but you should always cite anything you use (even readings from our course).
Do not use long and/or frequent direct quotations. Your source citations do not count toward your maximum word count. Note that in total you should be submitting THREE ~500-word responses as your final exam.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/course-instructions/paper_presentations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/course-instructions/paper_presentations/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Paper presentations Each student is expected to participate in two paper presentations. The average of each student&amp;rsquo;s score across these presentations will be used to determine the grade for the 20% of their coursework dedicated to paper presentations.
This is a groupwork project, but group members will have an opportunity to report on individual contributions. There are three primary components to each presentation:
Give a 10–15-minute live mini lecture that introduces your group&amp;rsquo;s paper, specifically covering:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/reading_questions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/reading_questions/</guid><description>Reading questions For each reading you are expected to demonstrate your understanding by responding to a handful of questions.
There are no right answers, but there are thoughtful answers. If you did not understand something, it is encouraged to be honest as long as you also outline what you did understand and what the primary barriers were for you to understanding more.
Reading questions are an essential component of each student&amp;rsquo;s participation grade.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2022/casillas-mind3-spring2022-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2022/casillas-mind3-spring2022-syllabus/</guid><description>Mind 3 (Section 9; Casillas) Spring 2022
Thursdays 11:00am-12:20am Chicago time
Office hours: Thursdays 1:00–2:00pm, or by appointment.
Instructor: Marisa Casillas (mcasillas@uchicago.edu)
Weekly assignments Wednesdays: Question and synopsis due before midnight Chicago time Thursdays in class: 1-question reading comprehension quiz Assignment descriptions Question and synopsis Post to Canvas discussion board (in this order):
A succinctly stated question directly derived from the week’s readings and lecture (two-three sentences at most). This should be a question that emerges from having understood the claims presented in the readings and/or lecture, not just a general question that one could ask of the topic without having read the material or heard the lecture.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2022/course_instructions/final-paper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2022/course_instructions/final-paper/</guid><description>Final paper Due dates Topic proposal: 11:59pm Tuesday, May 17 (via Canvas) Full final paper: 11:59pm Tuesday, May 31 (via Canvas) Instructions Overview Your final paper should be a coherent literature review of a specific topic that relates to the concepts covered this quarter. The paper should cover both current theories and empirical research relating to your topic. Thematically, your paper should build strong connections between your chosen topic and the broader themes of how context shapes psychological functions and processes.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2022/course_instructions/wk1-synopsis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2022/course_instructions/wk1-synopsis/</guid><description>Week 1 synopsis After reading and analyzing each of this week’s assigned articles by applying the methods outlined in the handout Guidelines for Mind (see Files/Guidelines for Mind (HenlyFallQ).pdf on Canvas), write a synopsis of one of them. Your synopsis should succinctly address the following questions (you should be able to answer most of these questions using 1 sentence or even bullet points, #4 and #5 may take a little more explanation).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2022/course_instructions/wk2to9-synopsis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2022/course_instructions/wk2to9-synopsis/</guid><description>Weeks 2–9 synopsis You will need to find and read an empirical article related to the week’s topic to present during our discussion. The goal of this assignment is to give you some experience 1) generating theoretical implications and hypotheses based on the readings and lectures, 2) searching the scientific literature to find empirical studies that bear on these hypotheses, and 3) presenting that research in a succinct yet comprehensible manner to an audience that is entirely unfamiliar with it.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2023/casillas-mind3-spring2023-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2023/casillas-mind3-spring2023-syllabus/</guid><description>Mind 3 (Section 12; Casillas) Spring 2023
Thursdays 11:00am-12:20am
Office hours: Book online here in Rosenwald 318A or Zoom (please indicate in your online booking)
Instructor: Marisa Casillas (mcasillas@uchicago.edu)
Grading 30% participation 40% weekly paper 30% final paper REQUIRED: 2hr of SONA credit Self grading For each assignment and for your participation, I will give you a rubric to self assess your work. You will then be able to give yourself a proposed grade, which I can accept or change.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2023/course_instructions/final-paper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2023/course_instructions/final-paper/</guid><description>Final paper Overview Your final paper should be a coherent literature review of a specific topic that relates to the concepts covered this quarter. The paper should cover both current theories and empirical research relating to your topic. Thematically, your paper should build strong connections between your chosen topic and the broader themes of how context shapes psychological functions and processes.
Your paper (formatting instructions below) should be written for an intelligent non-specialist.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2023/course_instructions/wkly-litrev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2023/course_instructions/wkly-litrev/</guid><description>Format 2: Literature review increments Your final paper will build on one or more of the lecture topics we cover this quarter. To ensure that you are ready to write a high quality final paper, we will begin on your literature review in advance of the actual final paper due date.
NOTE: You may choose a topic that we have not covered yet in class. If you do so, you will first need to read the papers assigned for that lecture before submitting your literature review components for weeks 7 and 9.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2023/course_instructions/wkly-syn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2023/course_instructions/wkly-syn/</guid><description>Format 1: Synopsis After reading and analyzing the week&amp;rsquo;s assigned articles by applying the methods outlined in the handout Guidelines for Mind (see Files/Guidelines for Mind (HenlyFallQ).pdf on Canvas), write a synopsis of ONE of them. Your synopsis should succinctly address the following questions (you should be able to answer most of these questions using 1 sentence or even bullet points, #4 and #5 may take a little more explanation). There are two varieties of synopsis, one for empirical papers and one for reviews—make sure you pick the right format for your paper:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/tr2-2023/casillas-tr2-fall2023-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/tr2-2023/casillas-tr2-fall2023-syllabus/</guid><description>Trial Research II Quarter: Fall 2023
Class: Mondays 1:30pm-4:20pm
Office hours: Book online here in Rosenwald 318A or Zoom (please indicate in your online booking)
Instructor: Marisa Casillas (mcasillas@uchicago.edu)
This is a workshop course to help you progress in drafting your master&amp;rsquo;s thesis. We will discuss practical writing strategies, share early drafts, give feedback, and learn a bit about academic publishing. By the end of the course you should have a first full draft of your paper.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/former-members/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/former-members/</guid><description>Former members Lab managers Kennedy Casey
Masters students Isabella Di Giovanni (MA 2023)
Erika Prado (MA 2022)
Jenny Bo (MA 2022)
Mary Elliott (MA 2022, UT Dallas)
Bram Puete (MA 2021, Radboud University)
Undergraduate students Emily Chan (BA 2023)
Kimberly Shorter (BA 2023)
Mia Rimmer (BA 2023)
Xuanyi Zhang (BA 2023)
Cam Friedman (BA 2023)
Carla Suarez Soto (BA 2023, UC Santa Barbara)
Will Fisher (BA 2024)
Mara Duquette (BA 2024)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/news/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/news/</guid><description>chatter news August 2023 Chatter Lab has temporarily relocated to Pick Hall while Green Hall is undergoing important renovations to increase building accessibility. We bid our farewells to Ruthe Foushee, Claire Bergey, and Kennedy Casey as they took off for their next exciting opportunities. Subin Kim joined the lab as the new lab manager. Sarah Sommer and Lizzie Mickiewicz presented their summer work in the lab at the College Summer Institute.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/people/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/people/</guid><description>chatter boxes Principal Investigator: Dr. Marisa Casillas Marisa (she/her) is an assistant professor in the University of Chicago&amp;rsquo;s Comparative Human Development department. Before coming to Chicago, she completed her BA (UCLA) and PhD (Stanford University) in Linguistics, followed by postdoctoral work at the Max Planck Institute for Psycholinguistics in the Netherlands. Her research draws on linguistics, psychology, and conversation analysis to investigate the foundations of human language cognition. She conducts observational and experimental work on adult and child language behavior in American English, Dutch, Tseltal (Mayan), and Yélî Dnye (isolate; Papua New Guinea), but maintains active collaborations with researchers working on other languages, including Sign Language of the Netherlands and Tsimane&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/positions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/positions/</guid><description>come join us! PhD students If you are interested in applying for a PhD in Comparative Human Development to work with Dr. Casillas, please get in touch with her. Include a CV and a brief description of what your mutual interests are and what you would like to know more about regarding the program and work in the lab.
Interns and research assistantships The chatter lab offers a small number of paid internships for undergraduate students who want to get short-term (3 month) hands-on experience with an existing lab project.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/projects/</guid><description>chatter lab projects and methods As an interdisciplinary lab, we work on a rather diverse array of topics using an even broader set of methodological approaches. We give a short introduction here to three of these research topics, giving some examples of methods for each:
Language development across cultural contexts
Real-time language use in interaction
Roots of linguistic identity
Multimodal conversational coordination
Language development across cultural contexts We conduct quantitative investigations into the early language environments and language development of children growing up in a variety of cultural and linguistic contexts.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/publications/</guid><description>chatter publications [ms] = manuscript, [sm] = supplementary materials, [gh]/[osf] = associated repository
Looking for tools?
selected preprints Bunce, J. P., Soderstrom, M., Bergelson, E., Rosemberg, C. R., Stein, A., Alam, Migdalek, M. J., &amp;amp; Casillas, M. (under review, September 2022). A cross-cultural examination of young children’s everyday language experiences. [ms]
in press/accepted Brown, P., &amp;amp; Casillas, M. (forthcoming). Childrearing through social interaction on Rossel Island, PNG. In A. J. Fentiman, &amp;amp; M.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/tools/</guid><description>chatter tools For your re-use or adaptation, here are some of the tools we&amp;rsquo;ve used to speed up data collection, annotation, and/or analysis in the Chatter Lab.
Making daylong audio recordings See the ACLEW site for the latest LENA-alternative tools.
See HomeBank&amp;rsquo;s tools repository for LENA-relevant tools.
Ethical considerations for daylong recordings.
Considerations to make before conducting daylong recording resarch.
Tutorial on getting started with daylong recordings.
Manually annotating child language environments DARCLE Annotation Scheme: An adaptable template and guidelines for child language environment annotations in ELAN.</description></item></channel></rss>