<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bios on chatterlab</title><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/</link><description>Recent content in Bios on chatterlab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/alexander-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/alexander-aboutme/</guid><description>[Alex]ander Stern (he/him/his) About me I am a third-year undergraduate student at the University of Chicago studying Linguistics and Urban Studies. I joined the chatterlab as a research assistant in June 2022. At the confluence of my academic interests, I want to investigate how language mediates an individual’s interactions with their society.
Contact Email: alexanderstern@uchicago.edu</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/carla-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/carla-aboutme/</guid><description>Carla Escalante (she/her/hers) About me I am a third year undergraduate studying linguistics and biochemistry at the University of Chicago. I joined the chatter lab as a research assistant in January of 2023. I am interested in language acquisition in early childhood, particularly in multilingual environments.
Contact Email: cdescalante@uchicago.edu</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/emily-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/emily-aboutme/</guid><description>Emily Chan (she/her/hers) About me I am a fourth year undergraduate student double majoring in psychology and economics at the University of Chicago. I am interested in language acquisition. In particular, I am interested in how early language development influences social categorization.
Contact Email: ewchan@uchicago.edu</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/erika-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/erika-aboutme/</guid><description>Erika Prado (she/her/hers) About me I am a PhD student in the Department of Comparative Human Development at the University of Chicago. I received my Bachelor of Arts degree in Psychology and a Minor in Sociocultural Linguistics from the University of California, Santa Barbara. While there, I was a McNair Scholar researching the embodied interactional practices of a nonspeaking autistic Latino teenager and his family members in order to provide fundamental insights into our understanding of human sociality as well as its complexities.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/isabella-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/isabella-aboutme/</guid><description>Isabella Di Giovanni (she/her) About me I am a second year PhD student in the Department of Comparative Human Development at the University of Chicago. I received my BA from Cornell University, where I studied Linguistics and Psychology with a minor in Cognitive Science. As an undergrad I worked with Professor Michael Goldstein and was involved in multiple research projects exploring early language learning in social contexts. Broadly, I am interested in language acquisition and development in social contexts, and in cross-linguistic and cross-cultural comparison.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/jordyn-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/jordyn-aboutme/</guid><description>Jordyn Martin Contact Email: jordynmartin@uchicago.edu</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/kennedy-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/kennedy-aboutme/</guid><description>Kennedy Casey (she/her/hers) About me I am the current lab manager. I joined the chatter lab in summer 2021 after completing my BA degree at Princeton University, where I concentrated in Psychology and also studied Cognitive Science, Linguistics, and Neuroscience. During undergrad, I worked primarily with Dr. Casey Lew-Williams, and my thesis research combined eye-tracking and corpus-based observational methods to investigate how infants learn and represent some of their earliest words.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/kimberly-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/kimberly-aboutme/</guid><description>Kimberly Shorter (she/her/hers) About me I am a fourth year undergraduate student majoring in Psychology with a minor in History. I am primarily interested in how social interaction affects childhood development. I joined the Chatter Lab in September of 2021 with the ImCo project.
Publications Casey, K., Elliott, M., Mickiewicz, E., Silva Mandujano, A., Shorter, K., Duquette, M., Bergelson, E., &amp;amp; Casillas, M. (2022). Sticks, leaves, buckets, and bowls: Distributional patterns of children&amp;rsquo;s at-home object handling in two subsistence societies.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/lizzie-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/lizzie-aboutme/</guid><description>Lizzie Mickiewicz (she/her/hers) About me I am a third year undergraduate student majoring in psychology and neuroscience at the University of Chicago. I am interested in exploring how cognitive processes influence language and vice versa. Specifically, I am fascinated by the idea of music as a language and means of communication, and I would like to study music medicine in the future.
Publications Casey, K., Elliott, M., Mickiewicz, E., Silva Mandujano, A.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/marisa-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/marisa-aboutme/</guid><description>Principal investigator Dr. Marisa Casillas Photo credit: Erielle Bakkum
About Broadly speaking, I am interested in exploring how cognitive and social processes shape the ways in which we learn, perceive, and produce language. My primary research examines the relationship between communicative skills and linguistic processing in children and adults. I use a combination of experimental- and observation-based methods to comparatively investigate these processes in both urban, Western contexts and rural, Indigenous contexts.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/mia-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/mia-aboutme/</guid><description>Mia Rimmer (they/she) Contact Email: mjrimmer@uchicago.edu</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/ruby-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/ruby-aboutme/</guid><description>Ruby Swensen Hi! My name is Ruby Swensen. I am in my second year as an undergraduate student studying linguistics with an emphasis in American Sign Language and a special interest in comparative human development. I joined the Chatter Lab in January 2023 excited to learn more about the many applications of language on human interaction and behavior. When I’m not studying or working in the lab, I love to go ice skating on the midway!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/sarah-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/sarah-aboutme/</guid><description>Sarah Sommer (she/her/hers) About me I am a third year undergrad double majoring in Comparative Human Development and English at the University of Chicago. I joined the lab in June of 2022 and I am interested in language development across different social and cultural settings.
Contact Email: ssommer@uchicago.edu</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/yuchen-aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/bios/yuchen-aboutme/</guid><description>Yuchen Jin (she/her/hers) About me I am a doctoral student in the Department of Comparative Human Development. Before coming to Chicago, I completed my BA in Education at Zhejiang University and Ed.M. in Human Development and Psychology at Harvard University. Broadly, my research interests include child lingusitic and communicative development, parent-child interaction, and in particular, how children become adapted to conversational turn-taking.
Contact Email: yuchenjin@uchicago.edu</description></item></channel></rss>