<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Archived_courses on chatterlab</title><link>https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/</link><description>Recent content in Archived_courses on chatterlab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/winter2021/casillas-bbc-winter2021-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/winter2021/casillas-bbc-winter2021-syllabus/</guid><description>Blooming, Buzzing Confusion Making Sense of Language in the First Few Years of Life Winter 2021: CHDV 23010
Tuesdays and Thursdays 12:30pm-1:50pm Chicago time
Office hours: Wednesdays 4:00pm–5:00pm Chicago time, or by appointment.
NOTE: This course is taking place remotely; email the instructor if you need access to the relevant meeting and coursework links.
Instructor: Marisa Casillas (mcasillas@uchicago.edu)
This course examines the social and cognitive mechanisms that drive language learning in the first few years of life.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/methods_presentations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/methods_presentations/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Methods presentations Each student is expected to participate in two methods presentations. Students earn up to 10 points (10% of the total grade) for each one.
This is a groupwork project, but group members will have an opportunity to report on individual contributions. There are three primary components to each presentation:
Give a 20-minute pre-recorded mini lecture that introduces a method and gives some sort of demonstration of how the method is implemented and how it appears to participants.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-1/</guid><description>Mini essay exam 1 Please use information from the readings, lectures, and in-class sessions to inform your answers. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to look up other sources, but you should always cite anything you use (even readings from our course). Be careful about re-using phrasings and concepts from out-of-class sources; there&amp;rsquo;s lots of information out there and not all of it is accurate. Your source citations do not count toward your maximum word count.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-2/</guid><description>Mini essay exam 2 Please use information from the readings, lectures, and in-class sessions to inform your answers. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to look up other sources, but you should always cite anything you use (even readings from our course). Be careful about re-using phrasings and concepts from out-of-class sources; there&amp;rsquo;s lots of information out there and not all of it is accurate. Your source citations do not count toward your maximum word count.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-3/</guid><description>Mini essay exam 3 Please use information from the readings, lectures, and in-class sessions to inform your answers. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to look up other sources, but you should always cite anything you use (even readings from our course). Be careful about re-using phrasings and concepts from out-of-class sources; there&amp;rsquo;s lots of information out there and not all of it is accurate. Your source citations do not count toward your maximum word count.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/mini_essay_exams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/mini_essay_exams/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Mini essay exams Three times throughout the quarter, undergraduate students will be expected to complete a mini essay exam. Each mini essay exam requires students to give ~500 word responses to two prompts. The exams are take-home and open-book; students have one week to complete each exam. Each exam is worth a total of 10 points (10% of the total grade) as follows:
Mini essay exam 1:
Response 1 (5 points max)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/participation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/participation/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Participation Participation points (up to 20 points/20% of the final grade) can be earned in two ways:
Active attendance during class sessions Visits to office hours The Winter 2021 quarter gives us 18 class sessions together (Tuesdays and Thursdays for nine weeks). Students receive 1 point for each time they actively attend a class (see below).
Students will receive 2 points for an office hours discussion with Marisa.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/reading_notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/reading_notes/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Reading notes This course includes up to 39 readings. Notes for required readings are due by the start of class. Please have your notes accessible during class.
Undergraduates
Undergraduate students will be assigned a total of 26 readings, but notes are only required for 24 of them. Each reading notes submission is worth 1.25 points each (maximum 30 points; 30% of the final grade). Students can choose for themselves which of the readings they would like to submit notes for.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/squibs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://github.com/marisacasillas/chatterlab/archived_courses/winter2021/course-instructions/squibs/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Squibs Over the quarter, graduate students are expected to produce six very brief (~1500–2500 word) papers on the topic of their choice related to course content. These &amp;ldquo;squibs&amp;rdquo; are used to engage further with ideas from the readings and, hopefully, to develop new ideas that can feed into the graduate student&amp;rsquo;s core work.**
What is a squib? Squibs are personal to your research interests—they are here for you to make concrete connections with what we are discussing in class and what you are thinking about in your Masters/PhD work.</description></item></channel></rss>