<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Courses on chatterlab</title><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/</link><description>Recent content in Courses on chatterlab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/casillas-bbc-winter2023-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/casillas-bbc-winter2023-syllabus/</guid><description>Blooming, Buzzing Confusion Making Sense of Language in the First Few Years of Life Winter 2023: CHDV 23010
Tuesdays and Thursdays 3:30pm-4:50pm
This course examines the social and cognitive mechanisms that drive language learning in the first few years of life. Nearly all children learn the language(s) of their community, despite the fact that human languages and caregiving practices offer immense diversity around the globe. What enables the learning system to adapt so robustly to the environment it finds itself in?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/methods_presentations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/methods_presentations/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Methods presentations Each student is expected to participate in one methods presentation. Students earn up to 10 points (10% of the total grade) for their presentation project.
This is a groupwork project, but group members will have an opportunity to report on individual contributions. There are three primary components to each presentation:
Give a 20-minute pre-recorded mini lecture that introduces a method and gives some sort of demonstration of how the method is implemented and how it appears to participants.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-1/</guid><description>Mini essay exam 1 Please use information from the readings, lectures, and in-class discussions to inform your answers. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to look up other sources, but you should always cite anything you use (even readings from our course).
Avoid long and/or frequent direct quotations and focus on sources. Your source citations do not count toward your maximum word count.
What is statistical learning? (300–500 words) Describe (a) what statistical learning is (at a broad level) and why researchers are interested in measuring it for language development, (b) describe at least three concrete examples of different types of statistical learning, and (c) relate the work on statistical learning that you mention to the idea of learning &amp;ldquo;mechanisms&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-2/</guid><description>Mini essay exam 2 Please use information from the readings, lectures, and in-class discussions to inform your answers. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to look up other sources, but you should always cite anything you use (even readings from our course).
Avoid long and/or frequent direct quotations and focus on sources. Your source citations do not count toward your maximum word count.
Writing a grant to study the noun bias (500–750 words) Imagine that you are writing to the university to secure funding so that you can conduct an study on word learning.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-3/</guid><description>Mini essay exam 3 Please use information from the readings, lectures, and in-class discussions to inform your answers. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to look up other sources, but you should always cite anything you use (even readings from our course).
Avoid long and/or frequent direct quotations and focus on sources. Your source citations do not count toward your maximum word count.
Blooming and buzzing, but confusing? (500–750 words) In this course we have covered four major factors that influence how children learn language (i.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini_essay_exams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini_essay_exams/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Mini essay exams Three times throughout the quarter, students will be expected to complete a mini essay exam. Each mini essay exam requires students to give ~500 word responses to two prompts. The exams are take-home and open-book; students have one week to complete each exam. Each exam is worth a total of 10 points (10% of the total grade) as follows:
Mini essay exam 1:
Response 1 (5 points max)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/participation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/participation/</guid><description>Participation as active attendance I will ask myself the following questions after each class session. If the answers are &amp;lsquo;yes&amp;rsquo; to at least two of the three, the student will receive full credit for participation that session. Otherwise the student will receive receive no credit for the session.
Did the student attend? Did the student ask one or more questions or comments? Did the student respond to questions from others or substantially contribute to group activities?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/d2m2022/casillas-d2m-winter2022-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/d2m2022/casillas-d2m-winter2022-syllabus/</guid><description>From Data to Manuscript in R Winter 2022: CHDV 20550/30550, MACS 30550, MAPS 30550, PSYC 30550
Tuesdays and Thursdays 09.30-10.50 Chicago time
Office hours: Tuesdays 11.00–12.30 in Rosenwald 318A or by appointment
Instructor: Marisa Casillas (mcasillas@uchicago.edu)
This course tackles the basic skills needed to build an integrated research report with the R programming language. We will cover every step from data to manuscript including: Using R&amp;rsquo;s libraries to clean up and re-format messy datasets, preparing data sets for analysis, running statistical tools, generating clear and attractive figures and tables, and knitting those bits of code together with your manuscript writing.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/d2m2022/course_instructions/instructions-data_selection_guidelines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/d2m2022/course_instructions/instructions-data_selection_guidelines/</guid><description>Data selection guidelines You must have a dataset to work with over the course of this quarter. It should ideally be a dataset that is urgently important to you and that you want to write up into a scientific report now/soon. Those in this &amp;ldquo;ideal&amp;rdquo; situation are certain to get the most out of this course.
What constitutes an appropriate, ready dataset is hard to comprehensively define. But here are a few core features that the dataset should have for the purposes of this course (and for quantitative/automated analysis and open, replicable science in general, though not strictly):</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/casillas-devcommcomp-spring2024-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/casillas-devcommcomp-spring2024-syllabus/</guid><description>The development of communicative competence Spring 2024: CHDV 38950, PSYC 38960, LING 38951, EDSO 38950
Tuesdays and Thursdays 15.30-16.50 Chicago time
Office hours: Book online here for a meeting in Rosenwald 318A or on Zoom (please indicate in your online booking)
Instructor: Marisa Casillas (mcasillas@uchicago.edu)
This course examines the emergence of communicative skills in humans. We will discuss the proposed cognitive, developmental, and evolutionary roots of communicative behaviors, with a focus on current gaps in our knowledge and possible pathways forward.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/instructions-debate_participation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/instructions-debate_participation/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Debate/&amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo; presentation participation Group debate: Turn-taking behaviors are universal to communicative systems There is one in-class debate planned in this course, and you will receive up to 1 point for your contribution.
In this debate, we will split up into groups and have a debate with one group arguing for the prompt and one group arguing against it. Groups will have a chance to work together to build their arguments and their response to the other group&amp;rsquo;s arguments.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/participation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/participation/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Active attendance The Spring 2024 quarter gives us 18 class sessions together (Tuesdays and Thursdays for nine weeks). Students receive 1 point for each time they actively attend a class. The last 2 points for participation come from contributions to the two class debate and turn-taking feature presentations.
Active attendance at class sessions I will ask myself the following questions after each class session. If the answers are &amp;lsquo;yes&amp;rsquo; to both, the student receives 1 point.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/reading_notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/reading_notes/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Reading notes Notes are only required for 30 of the readings assigned in this course. Students are allowed to pick which 30 readings to submit notes for. Each reading notes submission is worth 1.5 points (max 45 points). Of course students are welcome to take notes on all readings, if desired.
Notes for required readings are due by the start of class. Please have your notes accessible during class.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/research_proposal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/research_proposal/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Research proposal The research proposal makes up 20% of your overall grade, including up to 2% for your class presentation of the proposal and up to 18% for your full written proposal that is due during finals week. Students are encouraged to focus on research topics that either link to their other areas of expertise or their favorite topics introduced during the course.
Flash presentation of the proposed research Students will present the basic idea of their research proposal to their fellow classmates.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/transcription_mini_project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/transcription_mini_project/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Transcription mini project Transcription mini projects have three sub-parts, as follows: (1) Annotation and reflection submission, (2) proposal of mini research question, and (3) flash presentation of findings.
Annotation and reflection submission You will be asked to submit new annotations on your converation clips four times during this course. Each time you submit annotations, you should also submit a short paragraph reflecting on your experience. Each of the four submissions are worth up to three points.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/casillas-hli-spring2023-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/casillas-hli-spring2023-syllabus/</guid><description>Human language and interaction Spring 2023: CHDV 23100, LING 21150, PSYC 23120, EDSO 23101
Tuesdays and Thursdays 9:30am-10:50am Chicago time
Language may be learned by individuals, but we most often use it for communication between groups. How is it that we manage to transmit our internal thoughts to others&amp;rsquo; minds? How is it that we can understand what others mean to express to us? Whether we are greeting a passerby, ordering a meal, or debating politics, there are a number of invisible processes that bring language to life in the space between individuals.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment1-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment1-rubric/</guid><description>Mini assignment 1 rubric [main page]
Assignment evaluation questions In assessing submissions for mini assignment 1, the grader will ask themselves the following questions, answering each on the scale of:
0 = grossly incomplete/not addressed
1 = needs significant work
2 = minimally fulfills requirements
3 = good effort, but with room for improvement
4 = excellent and above expectations
A. Is the example thoughtfully selected?: The joint activity selected by the student should be a clear case of a joint activity that is highly distinct from the (many) examples presented in the readings, lectures, and questions that came up during lecture.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment2-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment2-rubric/</guid><description>Mini assignment 2 rubric [main page]
Assignment evaluation questions In assessing submissions for mini assignment 2, the grader will ask themselves the following questions, answering each on the scale of:
0 = grossly incomplete/not addressed
1 = needs significant work
2 = minimally fulfills requirements
3 = good effort, but with room for improvement
4 = excellent and above expectations
A. Is the game thoughtfully designed?: The schelling game should be clearly distinct from any of the examples in class.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment3-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment3-rubric/</guid><description>Mini assignment 3 rubric [main page]
Assignment evaluation questions In assessing submissions for mini assignment 3, the grader will ask themselves the following questions, answering each on the scale of:
0 = grossly incomplete/not addressed
1 = needs significant work
2 = minimally fulfills requirements
3 = good effort, but with room for improvement
4 = excellent and above expectations
A. Are the examples clear and creatively varied?: You should choose your examples from sources that we (the graders) have access to.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment4-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment4-rubric/</guid><description>Mini assignment 4 rubric [main page]
Assignment evaluation questions In assessing submissions for mini assignment 4, the grader will ask themselves the following questions, answering each on the scale of:
0 = grossly incomplete/not addressed
1 = needs significant work
2 = minimally fulfills requirements
3 = good effort, but with room for improvement
4 = excellent and above expectations
A. Do the selected gestures illustrate course concepts in a thoughtful or innovative way?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/scientificreport-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/scientificreport-rubric/</guid><description>Scientific report rubric [main page]
Please see the lecture slides on writing scientific reports before you read this rubric and make a plan for your paper.
Structure and format Your paper should have headings and subheadings with the following structure:
Title, student number, and word count Abstract Introduction Study 1 Method Results Study 2 Proposed Method Anticipated Results General discussion References It should be submitted as a Microsoft Word document (NOT a pdf) and should be 1.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/casillas-mcdr-winter2023-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/casillas-mcdr-winter2023-syllabus/</guid><description>Methods in Child Development Research Winter 2023: CHDV 23150, CHST 23150, EDSO 23150/33150, LING 33150, PSYC 23155/33150
Tuesdays and Thursdays 2:00pm-3:20pm Chicago time
This course engages with one current topic (the topic differs each year) from research on child social and/or language development. We will read and discuss a collection of research studies related to this topic to gain familiarity with its primary questions, theories, and methods. We will also, together as a class, conduct a replication of an experiment- or recording-based research study related to the topic.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/course-instructions/data_collection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/course-instructions/data_collection/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Data collection report Each student is expected to participate in at least one live data collection session, observing silently and under the supervision of a trained member of Dr. Casillas&amp;rsquo;s lab. Students are required to report on what they learned from the experience. The report can come in pretty much any form you can imagine submitting to Canvas: a brief (~0.5–1 page) written response to the questions below, a short story/poem/interpretive dance or song describing the experience, a collage or drawn/painted image, a sequence of relevant tiktoks, etc.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/course-instructions/final_exam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/course-instructions/final_exam/</guid><description>Final exam Please use information from the readings, lectures, and in-class discussions to inform your answers. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to look up other sources, but you should always cite anything you use (even readings from our course).
Do not use long and/or frequent direct quotations. Your source citations do not count toward your maximum word count. Note that in total you should be submitting THREE ~500-word responses as your final exam.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/course-instructions/paper_presentations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/course-instructions/paper_presentations/</guid><description>Grading guidelines: Paper presentations Each student is expected to participate in two paper presentations. The average of each student&amp;rsquo;s score across these presentations will be used to determine the grade for the 20% of their coursework dedicated to paper presentations.
This is a groupwork project, but group members will have an opportunity to report on individual contributions. There are three primary components to each presentation:
Give a 10–15-minute live mini lecture that introduces your group&amp;rsquo;s paper, specifically covering:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/reading_questions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/reading_questions/</guid><description>Reading questions For each reading you are expected to demonstrate your understanding by responding to a handful of questions.
There are no right answers, but there are thoughtful answers. If you did not understand something, it is encouraged to be honest as long as you also outline what you did understand and what the primary barriers were for you to understanding more.
Reading questions are an essential component of each student&amp;rsquo;s participation grade.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/casillas-mind3-spring2024-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/casillas-mind3-spring2024-syllabus/</guid><description>Mind 3 (Section 6; Casillas) Spring 2024
Thursdays 11:00am-12:20am
Office hours: Book online here for a meeting in Rosenwald 318A or on Zoom (please indicate in your online booking)
Instructor: Marisa Casillas (mcasillas@uchicago.edu)
Grading 30% participation 40% weekly assignments 30% final paper REQUIRED: 2hr of SONA credit Participation We use in-class time for clarification, discussion, and debate. If you have not done the reading for that discussion, you are encouraged to spend the hour making up the reading time on your own rather than attending discussion (seriously; just send me an email to let me know).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/final-paper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/final-paper/</guid><description>Final paper Your final paper should be a coherent literature review of a specific topic that relates to the concepts covered this quarter. The paper should cover both current theories and empirical research relating to your topic. Thematically, your paper should build strong connections between your chosen topic and the broader themes of how context shapes psychological functions and processes.
Your paper (formatting instructions below) should be written for an intelligent non-specialist.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/retrospective/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/retrospective/</guid><description>Retrospective Please submit on Canvas, as a Word document, Google document, or pdf:
1–2 paragraphs introducing yourself and any information you&amp;rsquo;d like me to know about you 1 paragraph each that describes the three Mind I/II lectures that have most impacted you and why (so, 3 paragraphs total). Remember that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t there, so please provide detail on content where relevant. 1 question for me (about whatever you like) [back to main page]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/wkly-debate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/wkly-debate/</guid><description>Debate preparation We will hold two debates in class this quarter. To make sure you are prepared to participate, I ask you to prepare notes in advance.
One week in advance of each debate, I will share a proposition that we will debate in the following class. Debates will span more than one lecture.
You are asked to prepare both affirmative and oppositional evidence and arguments in advance. In class you will be randomly assigned to one side of the debate and will work with your peers to refine and present your arguments.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/wkly-litrev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/wkly-litrev/</guid><description>Literature review parts 1 &amp;amp; 2 Your final paper will build on one or more of the lecture topics we cover this quarter. To ensure that you are ready to write a good final paper, we will begin on your literature review in advance of the actual final paper due date.
NOTE: You may choose a topic that we have not covered yet in class (i.e., from a future week). If you do so, you will first need to read the papers assigned for that lecture before submitting your literature review components for weeks 7 and 9.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/wkly-syn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/wkly-syn/</guid><description>Synopsis After reading the week&amp;rsquo;s assigned articles, write a synopsis for ONE of them. Your synopsis should succinctly address the points outlined below. You should be able to respond to most of these points using 1 sentence, though #4 and #5 may take a little more explanation). Bulleted responses are okay.
Please mark each response you give with the prompt title, e.g. with bolded text:
&amp;ldquo;Specific question: In this paper, the authors ask how&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/tr2-2023/casillas-tr2-fall2023-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/tr2-2023/casillas-tr2-fall2023-syllabus/</guid><description>Trial Research II Quarter: Fall 2023
Class: Thursdays 9:30am-12:20pm
Office hours: Book online here in Rosenwald 318A or Zoom (please indicate in your online booking)
Instructor: Marisa Casillas (mcasillas@uchicago.edu)
This is a workshop course to help you progress in drafting your master&amp;rsquo;s thesis. We will discuss practical writing strategies, share early drafts, give feedback, and learn a bit about academic publishing. By the end of the course you should have a first full draft of your paper.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/xlp2023/casillas-xlp-fall2023-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/xlp2023/casillas-xlp-fall2023-syllabus/</guid><description>Crosslinguistic perspectives on language development Quarter: Fall 2023
Class: Wednesdays 1:30pm-4:20pm
Office hours: Book online here in Rosenwald 318A or Zoom (please indicate in your online booking)
Instructor: Marisa Casillas (mcasillas@uchicago.edu)
This discussion-based course covers cross-linguistic evidence concerning similarities and dissimilarities in how children learn language across diverse language communities. Each year will revolve around a central topic. This year we will focus on the acquisition of phonology. Assignments are noted in green text.</description></item></channel></rss>