<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Courses on chatterlab</title><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/</link><description>Recent content in Courses on chatterlab</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/casillas-bbc-winter2023-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/casillas-bbc-winter2023-syllabus/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="blooming-buzzing-confusion">Blooming, Buzzing Confusion&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="making-sense-of-language-in-the-first-few-years-of-life">Making Sense of Language in the First Few Years of Life&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Winter 2023: CHDV 23010&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tuesdays and Thursdays 3:30pm-4:50pm&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course examines the social and cognitive mechanisms that drive language learning in the first few years of life. Nearly all children learn the language(s) of their community, despite the fact that human languages and caregiving practices offer immense diversity around the globe. What enables the learning system to adapt so robustly to the environment it finds itself in? We discuss the evidence for and against multiple factors that have been proposed to support language development across the world’s communities. We also critically examine how these ideas intersect with current deficit models of language learning.
It is expected that, by the end of the course, students will grasp the basic mechanisms proposed to underlie early language learning and will design a novel research project to test one of these mechanisms in infants or young children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/methods_presentations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/methods_presentations/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="grading-guidelines-methods-presentations">Grading guidelines: Methods presentations&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Each student is expected to participate in one methods presentation. Students earn up to 10 points (10% of the total grade) for their presentation project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a groupwork project, but group members will have an opportunity to report on individual contributions. There are three primary components to each presentation:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Give a 20-minute &lt;strong>pre-recorded&lt;/strong> mini lecture that introduces a method and gives some sort of demonstration of how the method is implemented and how it appears to participants.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Elicit and answer questions from the class about the method (~10-15 minutes). You are encouraged to use creative techniques to stimulate discussion.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fill out a peer evaluation form for yourself and your group members.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>In preparing the presentation, each group will be asked to inteview one researcher who has expertise in that method. The interview will be 20–30 minutes long and conducted in person or over Zoom. Interview scheduling will be coordinated by Dr. Casillas &lt;em>BUT&lt;/em> your group must provide draft questions and potential interview times &lt;strong>ONE WEEK&lt;/strong> (or earlier) in advance of your presentation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-1/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="mini-essay-exam-1">Mini essay exam 1&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Please use information from the readings, lectures, and in-class discussions to inform your answers. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to look up other sources, but you should &lt;strong>always&lt;/strong> cite anything you use (even readings from our course).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Avoid long and/or frequent direct quotations and focus on sources. Your source citations do not count toward your maximum word count.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-statistical-learning-300500-words">What is statistical learning? (300–500 words)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Describe (a) what statistical learning is (at a broad level) and why researchers are interested in measuring it for language development, (b) describe at least three concrete examples of different types of statistical learning, and (c) relate the work on statistical learning that you mention to the idea of learning &amp;ldquo;mechanisms&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-2/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="mini-essay-exam-2">Mini essay exam 2&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Please use information from the readings, lectures, and in-class discussions to inform your answers. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to look up other sources, but you should &lt;strong>always&lt;/strong> cite anything you use (even readings from our course).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Avoid long and/or frequent direct quotations and focus on sources. Your source citations do not count toward your maximum word count.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="writing-a-grant-to-study-the-noun-bias-500750-words">Writing a grant to study the noun bias (500–750 words)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Imagine that you are writing to the university to secure funding so that you can conduct an study on word learning. Your application will be reviewed by three professors in the social sciences, but you don&amp;rsquo;t know who. Explain the following: (a) what is the noun bias?, (b) what evidence exists for the noun bias?, (c) what are the reasons given to explain the noun bias, (d) where does the noun bias idea fall short (i.e., what &lt;strong>doesn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong> it account for)? Then, (e), give a brief description of the study you are proposing. &lt;strong>Novelty:&lt;/strong> Your study should not just replicate findings we discussed in class but extend them or re-examine them in some way. You can think of any study you want—it&amp;rsquo;s hypothetical after all—including bringing kids into the lab to run experiments, giving parents questionnaires, making recordings of natural interaction, testing different populations than we have seen in class, some combination of these things, you name it! Just make sure that your study somehow addresses an open question or shortcoming in the noun bias literature, as we have covered it in class. Please make explicit references to studies as needed (include at least two).&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-3/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="mini-essay-exam-3">Mini essay exam 3&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Please use information from the readings, lectures, and in-class discussions to inform your answers. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to look up other sources, but you should &lt;strong>always&lt;/strong> cite anything you use (even readings from our course).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Avoid long and/or frequent direct quotations and focus on sources. Your source citations do not count toward your maximum word count.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="blooming-and-buzzing-but-confusing-500750-words">Blooming and buzzing, but confusing? (500–750 words)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>In this course we have covered four major factors that influence how children learn language (i.e., our four &amp;ldquo;modules&amp;rdquo;): pattern recognition, cognitive biases, maturation, and environment. In each case we have seen how features of the child&amp;rsquo;s cognition and/or learning environment guide them in the process of language development. &lt;strong>Choose a SPECIFIC phenomenon that a child must learn during the process of language development.&lt;/strong> First, illustrate the challenge the child faces in learning this thing—what is blooming, buzzing, and confusing about it? Second, explain how each of pattern recognition, cognitive biases, maturation, and environment allows the child to make sense of this rich and noisy input in learning the phenomenon. Your response must have a clear illustration of the effect of ALL FOUR factors on the phenomenon&amp;rsquo;s development, so choose your phenomenon accordingly.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini_essay_exams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini_essay_exams/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="grading-guidelines-mini-essay-exams">Grading guidelines: Mini essay exams&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Three times throughout the quarter, students will be expected to complete a mini essay exam. Each mini essay exam requires students to give ~500 word responses to two prompts. The exams are take-home and open-book; students have one week to complete each exam. Each exam is worth a total of 10 points (10% of the total grade) as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/mini-essay-exam-1/">Mini essay exam 1:&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Response 1 (5 points max)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/participation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/bbc2023/course-instructions/participation/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="participation-as-_active-attendance_">Participation as &lt;em>active attendance&lt;/em>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I will ask myself the following questions after each class session. If the answers are &amp;lsquo;yes&amp;rsquo; to at least two of the three, the student will receive full credit for participation that session. Otherwise the student will receive receive no credit for the session.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Did the student attend?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Did the student ask one or more questions or comments?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Did the student respond to questions from others or substantially contribute to group activities?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Note that students with an excused absence for a class session will simply receive full credit for that session.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/d2m2022/casillas-d2m-winter2022-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/d2m2022/casillas-d2m-winter2022-syllabus/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="from-data-to-manuscript-in-r">From Data to Manuscript in R&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Winter 2022: CHDV 20550/30550, MACS 30550, MAPS 30550, PSYC 30550&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tuesdays and Thursdays 09.30-10.50 Chicago time&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Office hours: Tuesdays 11.00–12.30 in Rosenwald 318A or by appointment&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Instructor:&lt;/strong> Marisa Casillas (&lt;a href="mailto:mcasillas@uchicago.edu">mcasillas@uchicago.edu&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course tackles the basic skills needed to build an integrated research report with the R programming language. We will cover every step from data to manuscript including: Using R&amp;rsquo;s libraries to clean up and re-format messy datasets, preparing data sets for analysis, running statistical tools, generating clear and attractive figures and tables, and knitting those bits of code together with your manuscript writing. The result will be a reproducible, open-science friendly report that you can easily update after finishing data collection or receiving comments from readers. Never copy-paste your way through a table again! The R universe is large, so this course will focus specifically on: The core R libraries, the tidyverse library, and R Markdown. Students will also learn about the use of GitHub for version control.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/d2m2022/course_instructions/instructions-data_selection_guidelines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/d2m2022/course_instructions/instructions-data_selection_guidelines/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="data-selection-guidelines">Data selection guidelines&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>You must have a dataset to work with over the course of this quarter. It should ideally be a dataset that is urgently important to you and that you want to write up into a scientific report now/soon. Those in this &amp;ldquo;ideal&amp;rdquo; situation are certain to get the most out of this course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What constitutes an appropriate, ready dataset is hard to comprehensively define. But here are a few core features that the dataset should have for the purposes of this course (and for quantitative/automated analysis and open, replicable science in general, though not strictly):&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/casillas-devcommcomp-spring2024-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/casillas-devcommcomp-spring2024-syllabus/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-development-of-communicative-competence">The development of communicative competence&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Spring 2024: CHDV 38950, PSYC 38960, LING 38951, EDSO 38950&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tuesdays and Thursdays 15.30-16.50 Chicago time&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Office hours:&lt;/strong> Book online &lt;a href="https://calendar.app.google/g3mwVsxEbQAZHoDT6">here&lt;/a> for a meeting in Rosenwald 318A or on Zoom (please indicate in your online booking)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Instructor:&lt;/strong> Marisa Casillas (&lt;a href="mailto:mcasillas@uchicago.edu">mcasillas@uchicago.edu&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course examines the emergence of communicative skills in humans. We will discuss the proposed cognitive, developmental, and evolutionary roots of communicative behaviors, with a focus on current gaps in our knowledge and possible pathways forward. The course will consider these issues from multiple perspectives including linguistics, psychology, and linguistic anthropology, and will cover a wide range of methods used to analyze communicative cognition.It is expected that, by the end of the course, students will able to think and write critically about how human communication and human language are intertwined in both adults and children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/instructions-debate_participation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/instructions-debate_participation/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="grading-guidelines-debatefeature-presentation-participation">Grading guidelines: Debate/&amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo; presentation participation&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="group-debate-turn-taking-behaviors-are-universal-to-communicative-systems">Group debate: Turn-taking behaviors are universal to communicative systems&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There is one in-class debate planned in this course, and you will receive up to 1 point for your contribution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this debate, we will split up into groups and have a debate with one group arguing &lt;em>for&lt;/em> the prompt and one group arguing &lt;em>against&lt;/em> it. Groups will have a chance to work together to build their arguments and their response to the other group&amp;rsquo;s arguments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/participation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/participation/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="grading-guidelines-active-attendance">Grading guidelines: Active attendance&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The Spring 2024 quarter gives us 18 class sessions together (Tuesdays and Thursdays for nine weeks). Students receive 1 point for each time they actively attend a class. The last 2 points for participation come from contributions to the two class debate and turn-taking feature presentations.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="active-attendance-at-class-sessions">Active attendance at class sessions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I will ask myself the following questions after each class session. If the answers are &amp;lsquo;yes&amp;rsquo; to both, the student receives 1 point. Otherwise they receive 0 points.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/reading_notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/reading_notes/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="grading-guidelines-reading-notes">Grading guidelines: Reading notes&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Notes are only required for 30 of the readings assigned in this course. Students are allowed to pick which 30 readings to submit notes for. Each reading notes submission is worth 1.5 points (max 45 points). Of course students are welcome to take notes on all readings, if desired.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Notes for required readings are due by the start of class. &lt;strong>Please have your notes accessible during class.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/research_proposal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/research_proposal/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="grading-guidelines-research-proposal">Grading guidelines: Research proposal&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The research proposal makes up 20% of your overall grade, including up to 2% for your class presentation of the proposal and up to 18% for your full written proposal that is due during finals week. Students are encouraged to focus on research topics that either link to their other areas of expertise or their favorite topics introduced during the course.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="flash-presentation-of-the-proposed-research">Flash presentation of the proposed research&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Students will present the basic idea of their research proposal to their fellow classmates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/transcription_mini_project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/dcc2024/course_instructions/transcription_mini_project/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="grading-guidelines-transcription-mini-project">Grading guidelines: Transcription mini project&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Transcription mini projects have three sub-parts, as follows: (1) Annotation and reflection submission, (2) proposal of mini research question, and (3) flash presentation of findings.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="annotation-and-reflection-submission">Annotation and reflection submission&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You will be asked to submit new annotations on your converation clips four times during this course. Each time you submit annotations, you should &lt;em>also&lt;/em> submit a short paragraph reflecting on your experience. Each of the four submissions are worth up to three points.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/casillas-hli-spring2023-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/casillas-hli-spring2023-syllabus/</guid><description>&lt;!--
NOTES FOR NEXT TIME:

# more on what made annotation difficult after MD
what isn't obvious in annotation?
talk that is not on task
interleaving of talk about cards
multiple card references in one utterance
simultaneous completion points
version control in submitted versions
access to lab computers
... also weird DM recordings e.g., cut-outs and re-starts making need for media re-cutting/special re-alignment of annotations for OH


Info to add to the results that were presented in class
- remainder of student data
- common names for different images
- how often people change their placements
- how often the overhearers are leaving things blank
- if people are related vs. not affect accuracy (not this year)
-->
&lt;h1 id="human-language-and-interaction">Human language and interaction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Spring 2023: CHDV 23100, LING 21150, PSYC 23120, EDSO 23101&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment1-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment1-rubric/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="mini-assignment-1-rubric">Mini assignment 1 rubric&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../casillas-hli-spring2023-syllabus/">[main page]&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="assignment-evaluation-questions">Assignment evaluation questions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In assessing submissions for mini assignment 1, the grader will ask themselves the following questions, answering each on the scale of:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>0 = grossly incomplete/not addressed&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 = needs significant work&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 = minimally fulfills requirements&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 = good effort, but with room for improvement&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 = excellent and above expectations&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. &lt;em>&lt;strong>Is the example thoughtfully selected?:&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> The joint activity selected by the student should be a clear case of a joint activity that is highly distinct from the (many) examples presented in the readings, lectures, and questions that came up during lecture. The activity should be specific enough and described well enough for the grader to anticipate what features of the activity will be mentioned to qualify it as “joint activity” in Clark’s scheme. The activity should be specific enough that it merits at least a few sentences of description. If your chosen activity can be construed as general (e.g., “cooking a meal”), consider instead a specific instance of that activity (e.g., “an experienced cook and a novice cook making sushi together”) so that you can dig into your explanation with a rich imagined scenario and detailed examples of how the interaction qualifies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment2-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment2-rubric/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="mini-assignment-2-rubric">Mini assignment 2 rubric&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../casillas-hli-spring2023-syllabus/">[main page]&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="assignment-evaluation-questions">Assignment evaluation questions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In assessing submissions for mini assignment 2, the grader will ask themselves the following questions, answering each on the scale of:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>0 = grossly incomplete/not addressed&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 = needs significant work&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 = minimally fulfills requirements&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 = good effort, but with room for improvement&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 = excellent and above expectations&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. &lt;em>&lt;strong>Is the game thoughtfully designed?:&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> The schelling game should be clearly distinct from any of the examples in class. The game should be designed with a particular group of participants in mind, such that those specific group/community members tested can identify an effective coordination key to solve the problem successfully. Note that &lt;strong>excellently designed&lt;/strong> games will be set up such that those &lt;em>outside&lt;/em> the target group/community cannot necessarily identify the intended key, or may perhaps be drawn instead to another key. Your schelling game session should end with you briefly asking your participants to describe how they each made their decision. You are expected to report on how you identified and recruited participants, the exact wording you use to set up the game, any stimuli that you provide the participants, and how you record and assess the results. Your report should also mention what you &lt;em>predicted&lt;/em> you would find based on how you designed your game. Please be detailed in describing and justifying your choices in your game design.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment3-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment3-rubric/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="mini-assignment-3-rubric">Mini assignment 3 rubric&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../casillas-hli-spring2023-syllabus/">[main page]&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="assignment-evaluation-questions">Assignment evaluation questions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In assessing submissions for mini assignment 3, the grader will ask themselves the following questions, answering each on the scale of:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>0 = grossly incomplete/not addressed&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 = needs significant work&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 = minimally fulfills requirements&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 = good effort, but with room for improvement&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 = excellent and above expectations&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. &lt;em>&lt;strong>Are the examples clear and creatively varied?:&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> You should choose your examples from sources that we (the graders) have access to. That likely means giving us links to videos, audio recordings, or social media posts, but could also include things like attaching images of visual or textual signals if that is what you have decided to discuss. So, for each example, make sure to &lt;em>give us access to the original source&lt;/em> you got it from. All examples should clearly illustrate the difference between signal meaning and speaker meaning; it&amp;rsquo;s alright (even encouraged) if there is some &amp;rsquo;twist&amp;rsquo; or complication in the relationship between these types of meaning. The three examples should be chosen to illustrate the wide variety of ways in which these two meaning types can diverge. Ideally, your examples should be chosen to explore a &lt;em>clear theme&lt;/em> in signal-based communication of your choosing (e.g., exploring parallel differences in meaning types across multiple communicative modalities). Be creative in choosing these examples (and have some fun searching for them)!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment4-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/miniassignment4-rubric/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="mini-assignment-4-rubric">Mini assignment 4 rubric&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../casillas-hli-spring2023-syllabus/">[main page]&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="assignment-evaluation-questions">Assignment evaluation questions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In assessing submissions for mini assignment 4, the grader will ask themselves the following questions, answering each on the scale of:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>0 = grossly incomplete/not addressed&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1 = needs significant work&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2 = minimally fulfills requirements&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3 = good effort, but with room for improvement&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4 = excellent and above expectations&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A. &lt;em>&lt;strong>Do the selected gestures illustrate course concepts in a thoughtful or innovative way?:&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> It will be fairly easy to find examples of conversation with depictive gestures. A paper that goes &amp;ldquo;above expectations&amp;rdquo; will have examples that are not just &lt;em>clear&lt;/em> but illustrate a non-typical or unexpected case that put course concepts to the test in some way. For example, Holler &amp;amp; Wilkin&amp;rsquo;s (2011) study made the observation that depictive mimicry was a critical mechanism for grounding in the tangram task, thereby illustrating the special role that gesture can play above and beyond linguistic signals in conversation. That is a high bar of an example—we don&amp;rsquo;t expect anyone to make a groundbreaking discovery in their mini assignment. Rather we encourage you to keep an eye out for examples that strike you as complicated, interesting, or unexpected in some way and then to examine what it is about those depictive gestures that caught your eye, using course concepts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/scientificreport-rubric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/hli2023/scientificreport-rubric/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="scientific-report-rubric">Scientific report rubric&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../casillas-hli-spring2023-syllabus/">[main page]&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please see the &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1LHTzJKN9NuFEaAPJd_g50GUW9P7hcx0R0Pf_qrfZCzc/edit?usp=sharing">lecture slides on writing scientific reports&lt;/a> before you read this rubric and make a plan for your paper.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="structure-and-format">Structure and format&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Your paper should have headings and subheadings with the following structure:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Title, student number, and word count&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Abstract&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Introduction&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Study 1
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Method&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Results&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Study 2
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Proposed Method&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Anticipated Results&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>General discussion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>References&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>It should be submitted as a &lt;strong>Microsoft Word document&lt;/strong> (NOT a pdf) and should be 1.5 spaced Times New Roman or Arial font size 12 with one-inch margins all around. Please include page numbers at the bottom-center of your pages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/casillas-mcdr-winter2023-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/casillas-mcdr-winter2023-syllabus/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="methods-in-child-development-research">Methods in Child Development Research&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Winter 2023: CHDV 23150, CHST 23150, EDSO 23150/33150, LING 33150, PSYC 23155/33150&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tuesdays and Thursdays 2:00pm-3:20pm Chicago time&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course engages with one current topic (the topic differs each year) from research on child social and/or language development. We will read and discuss a collection of research studies related to this topic to gain familiarity with its primary questions, theories, and methods. We will also, together as a class, conduct a replication of an experiment- or recording-based research study related to the topic. Students should be prepared to read and discuss scientific research articles and to do hands-on research activities. Students will complete the class with expertise on the topic of focus, including experience with its associated methods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/course-instructions/data_collection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/course-instructions/data_collection/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="grading-guidelines-data-collection-report">Grading guidelines: Data collection report&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Each student is expected to participate in at least one live data collection session, observing silently and under the supervision of a trained member of Dr. Casillas&amp;rsquo;s lab. Students are required to report on what they learned from the experience. The report can come in pretty much any form you can imagine submitting to Canvas: a brief (~0.5–1 page) written response to the questions below, a short story/poem/interpretive dance or song describing the experience, a collage or drawn/painted image, a sequence of relevant tiktoks, etc. &lt;em>Some aspect of the report should touch on a subset of the points listed at the bottom of this page.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/course-instructions/final_exam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/course-instructions/final_exam/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="final-exam">Final exam&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Please use information from the readings, lectures, and in-class discussions to inform your answers. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to look up other sources, but you should &lt;strong>always&lt;/strong> cite anything you use (even readings from our course).&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Do not use long and/or frequent direct quotations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Your source citations do not count toward your maximum word count.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Note that in total you should be submitting THREE ~500-word responses as your final exam.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/course-instructions/paper_presentations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/course-instructions/paper_presentations/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="grading-guidelines-paper-presentations">Grading guidelines: Paper presentations&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Each student is expected to participate in two paper presentations. The average of each student&amp;rsquo;s score across these presentations will be used to determine the grade for the 20% of their coursework dedicated to paper presentations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a groupwork project, but group members will have an opportunity to report on individual contributions. There are three primary components to each presentation:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Give a 10–15-minute &lt;strong>live&lt;/strong> mini lecture that introduces your group&amp;rsquo;s paper, specifically covering:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/reading_questions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mcdr2023/reading_questions/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="reading-questions">Reading questions&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>For each reading you are expected to demonstrate your understanding by responding to a handful of questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are no right answers, but there are thoughtful answers. If you did not understand something, it is encouraged to be honest as long as you &lt;em>also&lt;/em> outline what you did understand and what the primary barriers were for you to understanding more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reading questions are an essential component of each student&amp;rsquo;s participation grade.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/casillas-mind3-spring2024-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/casillas-mind3-spring2024-syllabus/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="mind-3-section-6-casillas">Mind 3 (Section 6; Casillas)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Spring 2024&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thursdays 11:00am-12:20am&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Office hours:&lt;/strong> Book online &lt;a href="https://calendar.app.google/g3mwVsxEbQAZHoDT6">here&lt;/a> for a meeting in Rosenwald 318A or on Zoom (please indicate in your online booking)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Instructor:&lt;/strong> Marisa Casillas (&lt;a href="mailto:mcasillas@uchicago.edu">mcasillas@uchicago.edu&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="grading">Grading&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>30% participation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>40% weekly assignments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>30% final paper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>REQUIRED: 2hr of &lt;a href="http://uchicago.sona-systems.com/">SONA credit&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="participation">Participation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We use in-class time for clarification, discussion, and debate. If you have not done the reading for that discussion, you are encouraged to spend the hour making up the reading time on your own rather than attending discussion (seriously; just send me an email to let me know). You&amp;rsquo;ll have a chance to weigh in on your own participation grade.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/final-paper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/final-paper/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="final-paper">Final paper&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Your final paper should be a coherent literature review of a specific topic that relates to the concepts covered this quarter. The paper should cover both current theories and empirical research relating to your topic. Thematically, your paper should build strong connections between your chosen topic and the broader themes of how context shapes psychological functions and processes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your paper (formatting instructions below) should be written for an intelligent non-specialist. Organize your thoughts coherently, illustrate concepts with concrete examples, cite all scientific claims, and aim for clarity and persuasiveness over style.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/retrospective/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/retrospective/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="retrospective">Retrospective&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Please submit on Canvas, as a Word document, Google document, or pdf:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1–2 paragraphs introducing yourself and any information you&amp;rsquo;d like me to know about you&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 paragraph each that describes the three Mind I/II lectures that have most impacted you and why (so, 3 paragraphs total). Remember that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t there, so please provide detail on content where relevant.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 question for me (about whatever you like)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="../../casillas-mind3-spring2024-syllabus/">back to main page&lt;/a>]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/wkly-debate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/wkly-debate/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="debate-preparation">Debate preparation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We will hold two debates in class this quarter. To make sure you are prepared to participate, I ask you to prepare notes in advance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One week in advance of each debate, I will share a proposition that we will debate in the following class. Debates will span more than one lecture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You are asked to prepare &lt;em>both&lt;/em> affirmative and oppositional evidence and arguments in advance. In class you will be randomly assigned to one side of the debate and will work with your peers to refine and present your arguments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/wkly-litrev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/wkly-litrev/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="literature-review-parts-1--2">Literature review parts 1 &amp;amp; 2&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Your final paper will build on one or more of the lecture topics we cover this quarter. To ensure that you are ready to write a good final paper, we will begin on your literature review in advance of the actual final paper due date.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NOTE: You may choose a topic that we have not covered yet in class (i.e., from a future week). If you do so, you will &lt;strong>first&lt;/strong> need to read the papers assigned for that lecture before submitting your literature review components for weeks 7 and 9.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/wkly-syn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/mind3-2024/course_instructions/wkly-syn/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="synopsis">Synopsis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After reading the week&amp;rsquo;s assigned articles, write a synopsis for ONE of them. Your synopsis should succinctly address the points outlined below. You should be able to respond to most of these points using 1 sentence, though #4 and #5 may take a little more explanation). Bulleted responses are okay.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please mark each response you give with the prompt title, e.g. with bolded text:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>Specific question:&lt;/strong> In this paper, the authors ask how&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/tr2-2023/casillas-tr2-fall2023-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/tr2-2023/casillas-tr2-fall2023-syllabus/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="trial-research-ii">Trial Research II&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Quarter:&lt;/strong> Fall 2023&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Class:&lt;/strong> Thursdays 9:30am-12:20pm&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Office hours:&lt;/strong> Book online &lt;a href="https://calendar.app.google/9DB3dUzBffuLWqHA9">here&lt;/a> in Rosenwald 318A or Zoom (please indicate in your online booking)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Instructor:&lt;/strong> Marisa Casillas (&lt;a href="mailto:mcasillas@uchicago.edu">mcasillas@uchicago.edu&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a workshop course to help you progress in drafting your master&amp;rsquo;s thesis. We will discuss practical writing strategies, share early drafts, give feedback, and learn a bit about academic publishing. By the end of the course you should have a first full draft of your paper. Our mantra will be &amp;ldquo;writing is rewriting&amp;rdquo;. Assignments are noted in &lt;span style="color:green">green text&lt;/span>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/xlp2023/casillas-xlp-fall2023-syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chatterlab.uchicago.edu/courses/xlp2023/casillas-xlp-fall2023-syllabus/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="crosslinguistic-perspectives-on-language-development">Crosslinguistic perspectives on language development&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Quarter:&lt;/strong> Fall 2023&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Class:&lt;/strong> Wednesdays 1:30pm-4:20pm&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Office hours:&lt;/strong> Book online &lt;a href="https://calendar.app.google/9DB3dUzBffuLWqHA9">here&lt;/a> in Rosenwald 318A or Zoom (please indicate in your online booking)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Instructor:&lt;/strong> Marisa Casillas (&lt;a href="mailto:mcasillas@uchicago.edu">mcasillas@uchicago.edu&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This discussion-based course covers cross-linguistic evidence concerning similarities and dissimilarities in how children learn language across diverse language communities. Each year will revolve around a central topic. This year we will focus on the acquisition of phonology. Assignments are noted in &lt;span style="color:green">green text&lt;/span>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>